Finding Aid for Varsinais-Suomi Region immigrant letters, 1880-1966
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Varsinais-Suomi Region immigrant letters
1880-1966
Turun Yliopisto. Yleisen Historian Laitos.
2008061 Bd microcopy
The Institute of General History at the University of Turku, Finland (Turun Yliopisto. Yleisen Historian Laitos) microfilmed thousands of letters from Varsinais-Suomi (Southwest Finland) region in 1964. The letters were written by Finnish emigrants to their families and friends in Finland.
16 microfilms
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The microfilm were acquired in 1965. Project number 5574
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Institute of General History at the University of Turku began working on this collection of letters from Varsinais-Suomi (Southwest Finland) region in the fall of 1965. In October and November an agreement to collect letters was made with the Youth Society of Varsinais-Suomi Province and the high schools of the area. The instructions were printed in both Finnish and Swedish (Southwest Finland has a high concentration of Swede-Finns).
The Institute of General History collected the letters between February 1 and October 31, 1966. To begin this undertaking, the Radio of Finland aired several programs that made this project known. There were also several articles in Varsinais-Suomi newspapers. The letters were mainly collected by the local youth societies as well as private persons and other groups. Some individuals and groups received prizes for collecting the most letters. About 5,500 letters were collected, arranged, and microfilmed.
The Varsinais-Suomi Region immigrant letters consist thousands of letters written by Finnish emigrants from Varsinais-Suomi (Southwest Finland) region to their families and friends in Finland between 1880 and 1964. There are also post cards, diaries and passports in the collection. Many letters originate from the United States and Canada, but there are also others from South America, Australia, New Zealand and the Soviet Union. The Institute of General History collected the letters between February 1 and October 31, 1966. The collected letters were organized and microfilmed in the fall of 1966.
The collection was arranged by town (also known as parishes or municipalities). Within each town the letters of each recipient were kept together. The owners of the letters are in chronological order according to the emigrating year of their correspondents.
Every subseries of letters includes a questionnaire that was completed by the letter recipient. In the upper right corner of the questionnaire there is a code that includes the abbreviation of the town and the location of the sender.
The questionnaire for collecting these America letters contained the following questions:
The owner of the letters (name and address)
The writer of the letters (name and last address)
The relationship between the owner and the writer
When left for America
Who were they visiting in America
Why left
Home town in Finland
The occupation of the parents
How large was the family of the parents of the emigrant
Was the emigrant married when he left Finland
Did the wife and children emigrate, too
Did the emigrant get married in America
What year
The nationality of the spouse
The occupation of the emigrant when emigrated
Had the emigrant ever been working outside the home town before emigrating
How did the emigrant go to America (route and vehicle)
The first workplace in America
What kind of work
Where did the emigrant live the longest time in America
What kind of work
Other members of the group who emigrated at the same time: name, hometown, return to Finland
The later life of the emigrant: did/did not return to Finland
If applicable, why did the emigrant return
Return route and vehicle
Occupation after return
The number of the letters (photos, diaries etc.) in the enclosed questionnaire envelope
The owner donates the letters/loans them only for microfilming
The collector of the letters (name and address)
To be filled by the Institute of General History
Documents in this collection are identified with the following abbreviations indicating the name of the town or parish from which the immigrant came.
ALAS = Alastaro
AURA = Aura
B-DÖ = Brändö Al.
D-FJÄRD = Dragsfjärd
HAL = Halikko
HIIT = Hiittinen
HOUTS = Houtskari
JOK = Jokioinen
K-KERTA = Kakskerta
K-TI = Kalanti
K-LA = Karjala Tl.
K-NA = Karuna
KEM = Kemiö
K-KO = Kisko
K-JOKI = Kodisjoki
KORP = Korpoo
K-KI = Koski-Tl.
K-VI = Kustavi
K-TO = Kuuisto
KUUS = Kuusjoki
L-LA = Laitila
LEMU = Lemu
L-TO = Lieto
LOIM = Loimaa
L-TI = Lokalahti
MAAR = Maaria
M-LA = Marttila
M-KU = Masku
MERI = Merimasku
MIET = Mietoinen
MUUR = Muurla
M-KI = Mynämäki
NAAN = Naantali
ORIP = Oripää
PAAT = Paattinen
PAIM = Paimio
PAR = Parkano
PER = Perniö
P-LI = Pertteli
PYHÄ = Phyämää
RÖY = Pöytyä
RYM = Rymättylä
S-VO = Sauvo
S-RO = Somero
SUOM = Suomasjärvi
T-LO = Taivassalo
T-JOKI = Tarvasjoki
T-KU = Turku
USK = Uskela
VEH = Vehmaa
VEL = Belkua
VÄST = Västanfjärd
Y-NE = Yläne
Subjects:
Finnish Americans--Michigan.; Finnish Americans.; Finland--Emigration and immigration.; Immigrants--United States.; United States--Emigration and immigration.
- Alastaro, letters to
  - Aili Rantala
    - From: Willehard Helander. Australia, Fin, 1925; 135 items (Reel 1)
  - Eva Seppälä
    - From: Mauri Seppälä. S.D., 1961; 3 items (Reel 1)
  - Recipient Unknown
    - From: Sender Unknown. photo, 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Oskari Virkamäki
    - From: Sender Unknown. Wash., N.Y., 1913-1959; 59 items (Reel 1)
  - Hulda Kankare
    - From: Vilho Saila. Ont., 1915-1950; 5 items (Reel 1)
  - Kalle Kankare
    - From: Sender Unknown. photos, 2 items (Reel 1)
  - Recipient Unknown
    - From: Sender Unknown. photo, 1 items (Reel 1)
  - Fanny Maanpää
    - From: Viktor Maanpaa. S.D., 1945-1964; 28 items (Reel 1)
  - Lyydia Jaakkola
    - From: Sender Unknown. photos, 14 items (Reel 1)
  - Lempi Heikkola
    - From: Verneri Heikkila. Ont., B.C., 1929-1966; 56 items (Reel 1)
  - Sandra Rostedt
    - From: Emma Lehto. Conn., 1959-1961; 23 items (Reel 1)
  - Aino Hollo
    - From: Kyllikki Launovaara. Congo, 1959-1961; 4 items (Reel 1)
- Aura, letters to
  - Martta Saari
    - From: Joseph Saari. Calif., 1956-1969; 11 items (Reel 1)
  - Helmi Peltonen
    - From: various
      - Calumet, Mich., 1913; 1 items (Reel 1)
      - N.Y., 1915-1916; 5 items (Reel 1)
  - Sylvia Heikkilä
    - From: Vaino Heikkila, B.C., 1940-1965; 8 items (Reel 1)
  - Kaarina Hannula
    - From: various. Sweden, 1953-1966; 5 items (Reel 1)
- Brändö-Torsholma, letters to
  - Amandi Andersson
    - From: Alfred Henrikson. Wash., 1908-1955; 12 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Adolf Henriksson. N.J., 1904; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - From: August Nordberg. N.J., 1907; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Clifford Janson
    - From: Jonatan Janson. Calif, 1929; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - John Toren
    - From: Sender Unknown. passport, 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Sture Gustafsson
    - From: Alma Nelson. Pa., N.J., 1953-1965; 11 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Eliel Gustafsson. N.Y., R.I., Mass., 1957-1959; 7 items (Reel 2)
  - Elise Lindman
    - From: Olga Wiberg. N.J., 1965; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Selinda Lindman
    - From: Ellida Anderson. N.Y., N.J., Ohio, 1921-1945; 20 items (Reel 2)
  - Anni Lindman
    - From: Ellida Anderson. Ohio, 1956-1965; 13 items (Reel 2)
  - Tyra Törnroth
    - From: Ellida Anderson. no place, undated; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Ivar Lindman
    - From: Ellida Anderson. Ohio, 1959-1966; 7 items (Reel 2)
  - Edith Åkerberg
    - From: Florence Anderson. N.Y., 1964; 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Tyra Törnroth
    - From: Florence Anderson. N.Y., 1958; 1 items (Reel 2)
- Brändö-Fiskö, letters to
  - Anni Andersson
    - From: Viktor Blomquist. no place, 1951; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Märta Grahn, Hildur Orblom
    - From: Maria Lindquist, Karl Grahn. Manitoba, 1955; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Greta Östling
    - From: Ella Holmgren. questionnaire only. (Reel 2)
- Brändö-Lappoby, letters to
  - A letter for the Institute of General History (Reel 2)
- Dragsfjärd, letters to
  - Hilma Fagerström
    - From: questionnaire only. (Reel 2)
  - Sanfrid Asplund
    - From: Otto Asplund. questionnaire only. (Reel 2)
  - Elvira Frederiksson
    - From: Signe Eriksson. questionnaire only. (Reel 2)
    - From: Elvira Frederiksson. questionnaire only. (Reel 2)
    - From: Anni Karlsson. questionnaire only. (Reel 2)
- Halikko, letters to
  - Aili Tolonen
    - From: Hulda Mattsson. Skandia, Mich., 1966; 4 items (Reel 2)
  - Engla Kataja
    - From: Olga Holmes. Minn., 1959-1965; 35 items (Reel 2)
- Hiittinen, letters to
  - Ottilia Hollsten
    - From: Johan Stenroth. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Elna Rissen. Sweden, 1965-1966; 3 items (Reel 2)
  - Selim Westerberg
    - From: John Westerberg. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Bernhard Westerberg. N.J., 1945; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Erhard Hoglund. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Irene Ljung. N.Y., 1960; 2 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Wanda Swensson. N.Y., 1959; 2 items (Reel 2)
    - From: August Hogliind. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Ture Klemets
    - From: Axel Andersson. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Arne Rönns
    - From: Rolf Ronns. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
- Hiittinen-Högsära, letters to
  - Alfhid Pellaa
    - From: E. Isaksson., 1899; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - John Enberg
    - From: Karl Eriksson. no place, 1906; 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Dagny Vinge
    - From: Celia Sennorelia. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Ester Eriksson. N.J., 1960; 1 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Ivar Vinge Sweden., 1941; 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Alma Venberg
    - From: Oskar Venberg. no place, 1876; 5 items (Reel 2)
  - Ernst Stade
    - From: Selma Steinmitz. Fin, 1966; 6 items (Reel 2)
  - Anna Andersson
    - From: Abel Fagersten. no place, 1907; 4 items (Reel 2)
  - Johannes Blomquist
    - From: Nestor Soderling. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Axel Soderling. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Abel Helander. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Anna Johansson
    - From: Volmar Johansson. photos, 4 items (Reel 2)
  - Volmar Johansson
    - From: R. Berglund. Fla., 1966; 5 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Vivi Hagen. N.J., 1966; 4 items (Reel 2)
  - Eugenia Granlund
    - From: Sigrid Eklund. N.Y., 1964; 2 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Selim Eriksson. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Alfhild Pallas
    - From: Oliver Hagman. N.J., 1964; 3 items (Reel 2)
  - Eugenia Granlund
    - From: Gottfrid Eriksson. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Junia Boström
    - From: Emil Bostrom. N.Y., 1927; 4 items (Reel 2)
    - From: G. Soderlund. no place, 1932; 4 items (Reel 2)
  - Margit Högman
    - From: Vivi Carlsson. N.Y., Fla., 1961-1964; 7 items (Reel 2)
    - From: Rea Gustavsson. photos, 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Laida Lindström
    - From: Elvira Holmberg. photo, 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Anni Klemet
    - From: Artur Isaksson. Holland, Norway, Gibraltar, Scotland, N.Y., 1912-1918; 12 items (Reel 2)
  - Hjalmar Bergen
    - From: Emil Bergen. Australia, 1958-1964; 7 items (Reel 2)
  - Vivi Enberg
    - From: Vera Lenk. D.C., 1963; 4 items (Reel 2)
  - Rosa Hollsten
    - From: Olof Hollsten. photos, 2 items (Reel 2)
- Hiittinen-Rosala, letters to
  - Oskar Björkell
    - From: Artur Bjork. N.Y., 1945-1965; 5 items (Reel 2)
- Houtskari, letters to
  - Viktoria Henriksson
    - From: Viktor Henriksson. photos, 2 items (Reel 2)
  - Dagny Ringwall
    - From: Johan Holmstrom. no place, 1895; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Stig Ringwall
    - From: Henrik Nordquist. Australia, N.Y., 1891-1893; 2 items (Reel 2)
- Jokioinen, letters to
  - Ida Raemäki
    - From: Valma Halme. Conn., 1959; 10 items (Reel 2)
  - Sirkka Anttila
    - From: J. Alopaeus. Quebec, Ont., B.C., Idaho, Mich., Ill., 1955-1966; 24 items (Reel 2)
- Kakskerta, letters to
  - Ritva Palmunen
    - From: Oscar Hackley. Minn., 1965; 2 items (Reel 2)
- Kalanti, letters to
  - Aino Ellä
    - From: Amanda Aalto. Mass., 1925-1965; 24 items (Reel 2)
  - Aili Toivonen
    - From: Irja Heino. N.Y., 1961; 1 items (Reel 2)
  - Ellen Ellä
    - From: Richard Savon. Brazil, 1938-1958; 5 items (Reel 2)
  - Recipient Unknown
    - From: Nestor Rinne. N.Y., Sask., 1964-1965; 15 items (Reel 2)
- Karjala Tl., letters to
  - Aarno Nummelin
    - From: Nestor Nummelin
      - Vermont, 1950-1951; 2 items (Reel 3)
      - Detroit, Mich., 1960-1963; 3 items (Reel 3)
      - Minn., 1960; 4 items (Reel 3)
  - Kaarle Vuorinen
    - From: Juho Vuorinen. England, Ill., Va., Wash., N.Y., 1911-1964; 20 items (Reel 3)
  - Hilja Salminen
    - From: Nestor Hill. N.M., 1960-1965; 6 items (Reel 3)
  - Iivari Lehtinen
    - From: Oskari Lehtinen. Minn., 1965; 2 items (Reel 3)
  - Martta Ali-Haanperä
    - From: Jalmari Valtanen. Minn., 1946-1957; 15 items (Reel 3)
- Karuna, letters to
  - Sirkka-Liisa Ripsaluoma
    - From: Lenhi Luomanni. Ill., 1953-1965; 14 items (Reel 3)
  - Aili Lahti
    - From: Aune Korkioja. Sweden, 1965; 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Saima Alitalo
    - From: Kaarina Paimento. Minn., 1956-1969; 37 items (Reel 3)
  - Soilikki Vallunen
    - From: Sanelma Lahti. Ont., 1965; 2 items (Reel 3)
- Kemiö, letters to
  - Olivia Söderholm
    - From: Karin Kautto. Oregon., 1946-1952; 12 items (Reel 3)
  - Jenny Röblom
    - From: Erik Lindholm. Calif, 1958; 3 items (Reel 3)
  - Arvid Röblom.
    - From: Sivert Roblom. Australia, 1965; 11 items (Reel 3)
- Kisko, letters to
  - Anna Kavander
    - From: Fanny Kavander. Ohio, 1920; 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Agnes Saari
    - From: Elin Gronlund. Colto:, undated; 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Kalle Saarnio
    - From: August Sarin. Wash., Sweden, 1946-1954; 15 items (Reel 3)
  - Sylvi Vienola
    - From: Julius Maki. N.Y., 1964; 8 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Olga Maki. Calif., 1964-1965; 6 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Hilma Hilden. Calif., 1959-1965; 12 items (Reel 3)
  - Salme Salmela
    - From: Lempi Blom. Calumet, Mich., Detroit, Mich., 1964; 3 items (Reel 3)
  - Arvo Vuorinen
    - From: Aino Manelius. N.Y., Fla., 1930-1956; 8 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Anna Vuorinen. photo, 1 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Armas Vuorinen. photos, 7 items (Reel 3)
  - Fanny Turunen
    - From: Eemil Laine. Minn., 1961; 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Hellen Koivunen
    - From: Martta Manelius. photos, 3 items (Reel 3)
  - Siiri Grönberg
    - From: Hilma Salmi. N.Y., 1936-1965; 70 items (Reel 3)
  - Aili Vainio
    - From: Gust. Aarnio. Kaleva, Mich., 1938-1965; 22 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Femmi Mackley. Rochester, Mich., 1949; 6 items (Reel 3)
  - Mandi Aaltonen
    - From: Aina Saarinen. photo, 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Yrjö Lintunen
    - From: Pekka Kaisila. Brazil, undated; 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Airi Vaara
    - From: Anita Boutrup. Calif., 1963-1965; 7 items (Reel 3)
  - Sylvia Vuorinen
    - From: Paavo Karstrom. Ont., 1961-1963; 3 items (Reel 3)
  - Bertta Eklund
    - From: Emil Saari. N.Y., 1956-1965; 12 items (Reel 3)
- Kodisjoki, letters to
  - Johan Niemi
    - From: Sender Unknown. Va., 1906; 1 items (Reel 3)
- Korppoo, letters to
  - Naimi Eneberg
    - From: Axel Jahnsson, Calif., 1910; 2 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Naimi Eneberg. photos, 6 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Otto Hansson. Wash., Calif, 1956-1959; 6 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Vera Johansson. Ala., Calif, Wash., 1913-1965; 6 items (Reel 3)
  - Svea Andersson
    - From: August Tomasson. photo, 1 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Ulla-Stina Tjaden. photo, 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Manne Blomquist
    - From: Erik Blomquist. photos, 6 items (Reel 3)
  - Elly Eriksson
    - From: Selim Grondahl. photo, 1 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Fanny Kamb. photos, 2 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Svea Marchese. photo, 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Elna Andersson
    - From: Emely Engblom, no place, 1952; 2 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Linda Fredriksson. no place, 1955; 3 items (Reel 3)
  - Augusta Lindström
    - From: Viktor Fagerlund. Denmark, Minn., 1911-1918; 17 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Villiam Fagerlund
      - Minn., 1913; 1 items (Reel 3)
      - Detroit, Mich., 1945-1946; 7 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Matilda Jansson. N.Y., 1930-1932; 4 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Lydia Fossberg. N.Y., 1945-1950; 5 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Ida Karlsson. N.J., 1966; 1 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Konrad Lindstrom. photo, 1 items (Reel 3)
  - Hilda Eriksson
    - From: Herman Eriksson. England, N.Y., Minn., 1914-1917; 6 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Hilda Eriksson. N.Y., 1921; 3 items (Reel 3)
  - Satine Niininen
    - From: Hilma Hagberg. no place, 1961; 5 items (Reel 3)
  - Hilda Lindell
    - From: John Lindell. N.J., 1929; 8 items (Reel 3)
    - From: Frits Lindell. N.Y., 1921-1925; 3 items (Reel 3)
  - Edit Laakso
    - From: Emil Mattsson. photos, 2 items (Reel 3)
  - Satine Niininen
    - From: Valter Blomquist. questionnaire only. (Reel 3)
  - Selinda Andersson
    - From: Sender Unknown. no place, undated; 3 items (Reel 3)
- Koski Tl., letters to
  - Helvi Laakso
    - From: Helen Bonicalzi. Calif., 1956-1961; 22 items (Reel 4)
  - Lempi Helenius
    - From: Kaarlo Laakso. Minn., 1905-1909; 5 items (Reel 4)
  - Tuure Virtanen
    - From: Olga Linden. Wash., 1956-1962; 5 items (Reel 4)
  - Helmi Tammi
    - From: Emma Maki. Ohio, 1906; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Kaarle Mäkitalo
    - From: Manti Maki. Ohio, Calif, 1906-1930; 14 items (Reel 4)
  - Bertta Aaltonen
    - From: Matti Pukinoja. photos, 8 items (Reel 4)
  - Tyyne Salminen
    - From: Matt Korvola. Minn., Wash., 1947-1963; 8 items (Reel 4)
  - Hilma Nurmi
    - From: Waino Nurmi. Minn., 1957; 1 items (Reel 4)
    - From: John Nurini. Minn., 1948; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Aarne Ojanperä
    - From: Anna Ojanen. Wis., Ill., 1935-1964; 30 items (Reel 4)
  - Juho Virtanen
    - From: Lahja Ahola. Minn., 1965-1966; 3 items (Reel 4)
  - Elli Kankainen
    - From: Kustaa Kankainen. Fla., 1946; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Aksa Heikkilä
    - From: Karl Lehto. Minn., 1946-1969; 23 items (Reel 4)
  - Olka Virtanen
    - From: Elli Hendrickson. Canada, 1960; 2 items (Reel 4)
  - Lempi Lumme
    - From: Hilda Aalto. Minn., 1950-1964; 76 items (Reel 4)
    - From: O. Koskenlinna. Wis., 1950-1965; 63 items (Reel 4)
  - Leino Heikkilä
    - From: N. Nummi. Wis., 1947-1949; 2 items (Reel 4)
    - From: Anni Lampinen. Detroit, Mich., 1953; 1 items (Reel 4)
  - Risto Lindqvist
    - From: Reino Lindqvist. Minn., 1961-1965; 7 items (Reel 4)
  - Kerttu Suominen
    - From: Hilma Linnroth. N.Y., 1945-1949; 3 items (Reel 4)
  - Elvi Alhaisi
    - From: Charles Nummelin. Rock, Mich., 1957-1958; 2 items (Reel 4)
  - Maria Lappalainen
    - From: Hilma Heino. Minn., 1936-1949; 4 items (Reel 4)
  - Aili Könönen
    - From: Anna Heikkinen. Ohio, 1960-1963; 4 items (Reel 4)
  - Hilda Seppälä
    - From: Elina Linne. Sask., 1935-1936; 2 items (Reel 4)
    - From: Elina Linne. Sask., 1936-1962; 34 items (Reel 5)
  - Juho Paula
    - From: Pauli Paula. Brazil, 1956-1963; 24 items (Reel 5)
  - Raakel Paula
    - From: Pauli Paula. Brazil, 1933; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Keijo Kulmanen
    - From: Eeva Kattelus. Quebec, 1946-1949; 7 items (Reel 5)
  - Heimo Hailio
    - From: Vihtori Hailio. Ont., 1957; 2 items (Reel 5)
  - Martti Karp
    - From: Sinikka Riutta. Conn., 1954; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Saima Lindqvist
    - From: Milda Kokkonen. Alaska, Canada, 1961-1965; 7 items (Reel 5)
  - Reino Vataja
    - From: Rosa Sagalin. Fin, undated; 3 items (Reel 5)
  - Martti Haavisto
    - From: Hulda Lumme. from the ship, undated (Reel 5)
- Kustavi, letters to
  - Maire Virtanen
    - From: various. South America, N.Y., Md., Vt., 1892-1925; 12 items (Reel 5)
    - From: Aina Likitalo. from the ship, N.Y., Ohio, Germany, Pa., 1893-1900; 19 items (Reel 5)
  - Alma Ericsson
    - From: Josefine Baxter. N.Y., Fin, 1921-1955; 12 items (Reel 5)
  - Anna Leonsaari
    - From: Oskari Leonsaari
      - Africa, 1904; 3 items (Reel 5)
      - Winona, Mich., 1904; 1 items (Reel 5)
      - N.Y., 1915; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Albert Rantanen
    - From: Selma Lehtinen. N.Y., Minn., 1907; 7 items (Reel 5)
  - Elli Rantanen
    - From: Hans Lundstedt. N.Y., 1909; 2 items (Reel 5)
  - Josefiina Gustafsson
    - From: Elita Nyholm. N.Y. U items), 1911 (Reel 5)
  - Erkki Vahanne
    - From: Jalmar Saarelainen. Alta., Ill., Ohio, 1911-1961; 11 items (Reel 5)
  - Siiri Anttila
    - From: various. N.Y., Switzer, 1913; 20 items (Reel 5)
  - Ida Linden
    - From: Gustaf Linden. Miss., 1955-1958; 6 items (Reel 5)
    - From: Paul Linden. photo, 1 items (Reel 5)
    - From: Karl Linden. photo, 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Salli Vaihinen
    - From: Emil Saarinen. photo, 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Reino Aaltonen
    - From: Vaino Laine. Calif., N.Y., New Zea, 1925-1932; 8 items (Reel 5)
    - From: Alraa Sainio. Calif, 1929-1934; 3 items (Reel 5)
    - From: Viivi. Sainio. N.Y., 1912-1938; 5 items (Reel 5)
    - From: Jouni Laine. South America, Wash., 3 items (Reel 5)
  - Artturi Rantala
    - From: Frans Rantala. photo, 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Mr. Keskievari
    - From: Mr. Keskievari. N.J., 1908; 2 items (Reel 5)
  - Elina Valtonen
    - From: Emil Salo. Wyo., Wash., 1954-1969; 9 items (Reel 5)
  - Jenni Jokinen
    - From: Saima Siren. Mass., 1958-1964; 8 items (Reel 5)
  - Johannes Jokinen
    - From: Johannes Jokinen. photo, 1 items (Reel 5)
    - From: Anna Maki, Fla., 1959-1965; 19 items (Reel 5)
  - Iita Mäenpää
    - From: Hilta Saarinen. N. Y., 1907; 4 items (Reel 5)
  - Frans Kristo
    - From: Ferdinand Saarinen., 1907; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Inga Kristo
    - From: Wilhelmiina Varjonen., undated; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Frans Kristo
    - From: Alta Wilen. N.J., 1924; 1 items (Reel 5)
  - Ellen Lehto
    - From: Aino Saario
      - Calif., 1926-1927; 31 items (Reel 5)
      - New Zea, 1920-1931 (Reel 5)
  - Rauha Rouvali
    - From: Lempi Carlson. N.Y., 1946-1953; 5 items (Reel 5)
  - Jenny Salonen
    - From: Anna Jansson. Fla., Maine, 1946-1963; 29 items (Reel 5)
  - Helmi Mäntynen
    - From: Senja Lehtinen. N.Y., 1941-1957; 5 items (Reel 5)
  - Hellä Anttila
    - From: Arvid Rosenberg. Minn., Fin, 1926-1927; 2 items (Reel 5)
  - Verna Onsitalo
    - From: Eini Nelson. N.Y., 1951-1961; 4 items (Reel 5)
  - Santeri Lehtinen
    - From: Senja Lehtinen. N.Y., Conn., 1963-1965; 14 items (Reel 5)
  - Aarne Nieminen
    - From: Wilma Nieminen. N.Y., 1939-1966; 17 items (Reel 6)
  - Signe Viisola
    - From: Selma Larsen. N.Y., New Zealand, 1 items (Reel 6)
  - Tilda Vartiala
    - From: Loviisa Iitti. Calif., 1956; 3 items (Reel 6)
  - Eini Numminen
    - From: A. Viljanen. N.Y., 1957-1963; 15 items (Reel 6)
  - Viljo Friberg
    - From: Jalmar Laiho. R.I., N.Y., 1950-1961; 23 items (Reel 6)
  - Agda Säynäslahti
    - From: Lauri Manner, D.C., 1959-1963; 2 items (Reel 6)
  - Teuvo Saario
    - From: Joh. Saario. Photos, 4 items (Reel 6)
  - Alli Saarikkola
    - From: Ella Fitzgerald, N.J., 1964; 1 items (Reel 6)
  - Milja Kallio
    - From: Kustaa Renvall. N.Y., 1946; 2 items (Reel 6)
  - Ossian Kuusinen
    - From: Kustaa Kanerva, Sulo Kanerva. New Zealand, Australia, 1924-1938; 4 items (Reel 6)
  - Edvin Elo
    - From: various. N.Y., Vt., 1910-1923; 18 items (Reel 6)
  - Maria Elo. questionnaire only. (Reel 6)
  - Hellin Marjanen. questionnaire only. (Reel 6)
  - Olavi Marjanen. questionnaire only. (Reel 6)
  - Anja Engdahl
    - From: Naima Heinonen. Ont., N.Y., 1927-1932; 4 items (Reel 6)
    - From: Mary Eskola. Ont., 1956-1962; 4 items (Reel 6)
    - From: Annikki Pohja. Mass., 1957; 1 items (Reel 6)
  - Tyyne Sundberg
    - From: Frans Sjoman. N.Y., 1964; 1 items (Reel 6)
  - Kustaa Marjanen
    - From: Oiva Marjanen. Argentina, 1946-1966; 10 items (Reel 6)
  - The Kanervas
    - From: Kustaa Kanerva. Australia, New Zea, 1921-1931; 19 items (Reel 6)
  - Mr. Nummela
    - From: Albin Koivisto. photo, 1 items (Reel 6)
  - Fino Kortelin
    - From: Vihtori Kortelin. photo, 1 items (Reel 6)
  - Hellä Anttila
    - From: Hilma Koski., 1961; 1 items (Reel 6)
  - Hilkka Lehtinen